You save for 10-15 years for your children's education,
but
if you die during this time, the insurance
company will pay your premium and your children will
receive the full amount for their education.
Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajpat,
and today I am presenting to you a
child plan. Hello friends, my name is
Anil Rajpat, and today I
am presenting to you a child plan, where I am
showing you the best plans.
I am not presenting plans from just one company, from different companies.
You need immediate income, long-
term income, short-term income.
You need plans with market-based returns, you
need a 100% guaranteed plan.
I have
chosen different plans according to different needs. In all cases,
if the breadwinner in the family dies, the
company will pay the premium. The benefits will continue.
You and your family will
not have to compromise with your savings
or your children's education. So, let's see
what kind of plans are there and
watch this video completely. If you like the plan, if you
like my video, then I have
such an option.  There is a rider or an
inbuilt feature under which if the
proposer who pays the premium dies, that is, the
father or mother dies
and the insurance is for the child, then the
premium payment is waived and the policy
benefits continue. The
child also gets the maturity of the policy, that is,
suppose your objective was that the child should get a certain
amount for his education. Now
suppose you die while paying the premium,
then how will you pay the premium? The
breadwinner dies, your wife is a housewife, and the
household expenses are barely being met,
how will you pay the insurance premium? If
you have taken a waiver and premium rider, then the
premium payment will be waived. The company will
pay it for you and you will
get the maturity. This maturity will be available even if you are alive and even if
you die, that is,
you are sure that your child's education will
definitely be good. So, if you
buy a policy keeping the children's education in mind, then always check whether the waiver of premium
rider is there in it or not.
If it is there, then only make the purchase, otherwise you will have to get up tomorrow.  If
something happens to you, it
can be very difficult to pay the premium. If you are not able to pay the policy, then the
policy will lapse. So it is better
that you buy the policy only after adding waiver of premium rider.
If your objective
is a 100% guaranteed plan for children's education, under this plan
you have to
save 00 months for the next 12 years
and you will get guaranteed maturity at the age of 18 only. You will find
guarantee written here,
you will get guaranteed ₹4410.
This is a
product of a different company. Under this company's
product, you will get waiver of
premium rider, that is, suppose you
paid the first premium and you die, the
company will pay the premium of the remaining 11 years of ₹1200
itself
and your child will get ₹44000, that too
100%
guaranteed. So this is a good feature, but if the
child dies because it is insured in this, then if the
child dies, then the
policy gets closed after getting ₹860000, but if the person paying it dies, that is, if
the proposer, that is,
In this policy, the father
is the proposer and the child is the life insured and if the father
dies, then the premium will be waived
and ₹ 44000 will be given 100%, that is,
you have paid ₹ 1000000 and
you got ₹ 44000 against it, so this
is a guaranteed plan in this way, it is
not related to the share market, it is not related to any bonus,
you can see the next plan in the same
way that you paid ₹ 0000 and
you want maturity in the 20th year, on which guarantee will be
written and if you see in the guarantee,
3569 280 is written, then
you will definitely get this 3569000, so now you will see that you are paying for
20 years, 10 years and you have to take the money in the 20th year,
so according to this one goal, you
can see which type of plan you have to
purchase, the
next option is for short term income,
brother, one for one year, 10 years and you are
getting money for 20 years  Yes, you are thinking that
you will get money every year and if there is a
rider of waiver of premium then you have to
pay Rs. 00 per month for 12 years,
you have to wait for one year, then for the next 12 years
you will get an
income of Rs. 8416 and this too will be 100 percent
guaranteed for you, here you see,
for the next 12 years you are getting this income of Rs.
84000, you paid Rs. 1200, in front of that there
is a guaranteed income of Rs. 8496, if you pay one premium
or five premiums, if you die then the
company will pay the remaining seven premiums and your children will definitely get an income of Rs. 28400.
Now let us see another option where you
get immediate income, did you pay the premium of Rs.
00, suppose in 2023, then immediately
in one year, from the first year itself, you will
start getting a guaranteed income of Rs. 50460, immediately
from the first year itself and this will come every year, for how many
years will it come, for the next 40 years you  You
can take this guaranteed income and in the end you will
also get a maturity of Rs. 000, that is, technically
how much money is going out of your pocket, that you are
getting 50 back, out of 1200, 7 are
going out of your pocket, okay, and after that
50000 is also coming and maturity is also coming,
now in this also if there is a death while the premium is increasing,
suppose if you die after paying three premiums, then the
company will pay the remaining nine premiums, the
income of Rs. 50000 will start and the maturity of Rs. 20 lakh will also
come, the maturity of Rs. 20 lakh will
also come, all these plans that
I am telling you now are 100 percent guaranteed
plans, neither related to the share market,
nor is it a ULIP, nor is it related to bonus, the one that
I told about short term income, which is for 10 years, for
20 years and the one that is told about income,
this is a 100 percent guaranteed plan, let me tell you about
a plan, this is a plan with bonus,
where you have to pay premium for 15 years, the
match will come after 20 years  The child's age is
5 years, your age is 35 years and here
you are paying a premium of around Rs 1 lakh for 15
years. So, you will see that after 15 years, you will get Rs
165,000 for the children's education till the next five years. You will get a guarantee written on it. This Rs
165,000 will come to you for 5 years and the
maturity will be bonus based. If
you look at column number 12,
you will get Rs 19,22,250 on maturity based on bonus.
If the bonus comes to 4, you will get Rs 990,000
but this Rs 165,000 will be guaranteed. So,
you can also purchase this policy where
you have to pay premium for 15 years.
You will reach maturity at 20 years and you are getting bonus
based benefits in this policy.
Tell me about another plan where you can take a
rider for the children and premium and
you can also purchase a policy for long term up to 85 years.
Suppose your age is 35 years
and you are the proposer in this policy.  In life
insurance also, your child is only the nominee. In that
case, you paid a premium of Rs 1 lakh each.
Suppose you paid a premium for 10 years
and if you look at column number 17,
you will get an income of Rs 023 from the first year itself.
This is bonus based, so you will get an income of Rs 023 till the
next year when you will be 85. And
on maturity also you will
get Rs 26693. Now, if you die, that is, the
father who is the earning member,
who is insured and has
also taken this inbuilt rider, where if you
die, suppose if you die in the fourth year, then
your insurance of Rs 11 lakh at that time will be given
to your children. The entire Rs 11 lakh i.e.
income of Rs 35000 will continue to be given to the child
and the Rs 24 lakh that you are going to get on maturity will
also be given to the children. In
this way, as per your need, you can
select a plan for short term, long term, lump sum, immediate income, bonus based income or income till the age of 85.
Waiver of premium rider is available in all these plans. In
Capital Guarantee Solution, when you
search online on the internet or on a website,
you will often see
products with Capital Guarantee Solution. Capital Guarantee
Solution means where two
products are combined, one is a ULIP
plan and one is a guaranteed plan
and by combining both, you are
shown products. For example, you will be told that
you have to pay Rs. 9000 or Rs. 0000 for 10 years
and you will get approximately Rs. 2
crore 30 lakh or Rs. 2 crore 3 lakh in 21 years
because they have
shown the plans there according to their current fund performance in the market. So
if you want to invest in ULIP
and want capital guarantee,
in Capital Guarantee, there will be the second portion. The
portion of guaranteed products will be the same.
Here you can see with an example, I will
try to explain to you that here
you are
paying a premium of Rs. 9916.
Look here in this premium.  But
you will also see the solution of % and the
returns will also be visible here, so this one which
you are seeing as
122000 is in a guaranteed plan, you
login and the policy is taken, the second one is
in the ULI policy, the
table is given at 4 and 8,
IRD is on S, from 8 it becomes 15 lakh 71000
and if the past performance is good or fund
performance is good then that value can go into crores of rupees
and can also go into minus,
so when you purchase the policy, it is
important for you to keep in mind whether you
want this type of plan or not, so
first you have to select whether you
want a guaranteed plan or your ability to take risk,
waiver and premium rider are available in both these plans, that is,
if the person taking the policy dies, then the
premium will be waived,
the company will pay the premium and your benefits will continue,
so here you will notice that the
premium you paid in 10 years is
around Rs 12 lakh, this will cost you  You get back Rs 12 lakh,
hence it is
called Capital Guarantee. I will try to explain how these two plans are different. The
first one is like for example,
if I look at the Capital Guarantee
Solution of TI, then the first plan in it
is 4tune Pr where it is a Uniline policy
and here suppose the age of the child is 5
years, the person is 35 years, the
premium will be payable for 10 years, maturity will
come at the age of 21, you are paying monthly and annually, in this
way you are getting 11 funds for
investment, you
can invest anywhere and here waiver of
premium rider has been taken for you, that is,
on maturity the premium increase is waived, the
company pays it and
here you get market based returns
because this is the table at 4 and 8 from the name of IRDA,
so here you will see only Rs 1571000, the
actual return can be more
or less than this, that second plan will be
added here like Smart  It is
called Income Plus. It is a guaranteed plan, non-
linked, non-participating, which means it neither
participates in the bonus nor is it a ULIP
policy. The child is 5 years old, 35
years old, 10 years old, and reaches maturity at 21 years.
You will notice here
that 'Guaranteed' will be written on the returns.
At 20 years, you will get Rs 61,000.
At 21 years also, you will get Rs 61,000 in total. You will get Rs
122,000. In this way, if you have
deposited Rs 12 lakh in both the plans together, then you will
get Rs 12 lakh back. This is called Capital Guarantee. So,
if you
want to take a solution with capital guarantee, it is your choice. The first
plan is that you can take the capital guarantee option
with waiver of premium rider for
your children's education.
Similarly, you
can also look at HDFC. They also launch a capital guarantee
product where they have a
plan by investing the entire corpus in the ULIP policy.
You can purchase that with waiver of premium
rider and there you will get market based
returns.
You can see it here and
along with that they have a guaranteed plan
called SASE Fixed Match Plan so
you can also take that product with rider
so here you will see that you get a match of 12 lakhs
so if you combine both the plans then
you will get 12 lakhs back after increasing the premium
and according to ULIP
your return will be your market base
return and this will be your capital guarantee
₹1 lakh because here you have to pay ₹18000
premium and in ULIP plan you have to pay
around 000 premium so this will
be capital guarantee solution this
is available with most of these companies where
you can purchase the policy by combining two products
so if you liked this video of mine
and you want to purchase any of these policies
then you can contact me
on 9909 4034 122 my name
is Anil Rajpat and before leaving my message